ALICE HOUEL

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

I am a Software Engineer with a winemaking background, who is passionate about music and making a positive social impact. Known for my audacity and tenacity, I love solving problems, learning new skills and sharing them, writing clean code and shipping features with beautiful UX. As a Winemaker then and as an Engineer now, I deeply care about the quality of the product I craft and providing users with the best experience possible while improving their life.

CONTACT ME

Mobile: (503)703-6536

Email: amhouel@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/alicehouel GitHub: www.github.com/amhouel

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Production planning (short- and longterm)
- Staff training & supervising
- Communication skills with multidisciplinary teams, suppliers & clients
- Professionalism
- Leadership

TECHNICAL SKILLS

• Front-End:

HTML5 | CSS3 | Javascript | Typescript | React | React Native | React Native Web | React | Admin | Redux | Styled Components | CSS | Modules | AJAX

• Back-End:

Node.js | Express | PostgreSQL & Sequelize | MongoDB & Mongoose | Hasura | Python

EDUCATION

General Assembly, New YorkWeb Development Immersive Certificate

University of Reims, Champagne-Ardenne, France

Master's Degree in Enology & Viticulture

Burgundy Business School, France

Master's Degree in Wine and Spirits International Marketing

Polytech'Lille, France

Master's Degree in Food Processing Engineering

EXPERIENCE

Product Engineer - Frontend | Reach Progress PBC, New York

December 2018 - present

Early stage civic tech startup developing a web and mobile organizing application for progressive grassroots political campaigns and non-profit organizations:

- Working in close collaboration in an agile environment with our Product Manager, UX
 Designer and Backend Engineers
- Developing new features and improving existing ones for our:
 - React/Redux web app
 - React Native/ Expo mobile app
 - React Admin/ Hasura admin app
- Creating React Native Web components shareable between our mobile app and web
- Converting our javascript codebase to typescript
- Fixing bugs
- Writing integration tests with Cypress
- Reviewing code
- · Contributing on the Backend

Teaching Assistant Volunteer | Code Nation, New York

October 2019 - March 2020

Teacher Led Web Development Program at the Academy Of Innovative Technology:

- Helping 10th grade students understand/learn HTML, CSS, JQuery and Javascript
- Guiding them in completing their homework and projects

Engineering Fellow | General Assembly, New York

August 2018 - October 2018

- 12 week Web Development Immersive (WDI)
- 4 projects designed including the Give Back NYC app, where volunteers can find
 volunteering opportunities in their community in NYC, log their experiences and rate
 them. Volunteers get points for each rated experience. This is a full-stack, responsive,
 web application built with ReactJS, CSS flexbox and grid, NodeJS, Express and
 PostgreSQL with the Sequelize ORM.
- https://give-back-nyc.herokuapp.com/

Winemaker | City Winery New York, NY

February 2017 - July 2018

- Production planning (short- and long-term)
- Staff hiring, training & supervising of permanent & seasonal workers (up to 15 each year) & newly hired winemakers
- Communicating with multi-disciplinary teams, suppliers & 5 clients